<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    
    <title>Jeff</title>
    <description></description>
    <link>https://jeffvansteijn.nl/</link>
    
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Copyright 2024, Calvin Tran</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 20:20:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Hugo - gohugo.io</generator>
    <docs>http://cyber.harvard.edu/rss/rss.html</docs>
    <atom:link href="https://jeffvansteijn.nl//atom.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/>
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I made this website</title>
      <link>https://jeffvansteijn.nl/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It serves as a space where I can introduce myself, showcase my favorite work, and as sort of a personal note-taking/journal. Let me begin with the introduction; perhaps I&amp;rsquo;ll add some showcases later. When you land on the page, you might be surprised by its simple and minimalistic approach. Let me explain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As most of the designers know, working on your portfolio can be a hell of a job! The ever-changing digital trends, never being satisfied, and often limited front-end skills. All this influenced my decision to opt for this minimalistic yet timeless design. (I might occasionally spice it up, but don’t expect anything too fancy.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;audience&#34;&gt;Audience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Those who know me are aware that I&amp;rsquo;m not the most outspoken or &amp;ldquo;show off&amp;rdquo; individual. I prefer to keep a low profile, which is why I primarily created this page for myself, with some consideration for other visitors, likely fellow designers, product people or cycling enthusiasts?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;writing&#34;&gt;Writing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Yes, I&amp;rsquo;ve added a blog. Here, I will attempt to write about various topics, mainly focused on design. Now, do not expect groundbreaking articles; rather, it&amp;rsquo;s my perspective on random subjects within the field. As I will always add new content, I may change your mind about older posts.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
      <author></author>
      <guid>https://jeffvansteijn.nl/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Apr 2024 20:20:11 +0200</pubDate>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
